<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andreas Flakstad</title>
    <link>https://andreasflakstad.no/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andreas Flakstad</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://andreasflakstad.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard-First Outlining</title>
      <link>https://andreasflakstad.no/posts/keyboard-first-outlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreasflakstad.no/posts/keyboard-first-outlining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I’ve had to manage projects, I’ve disliked the tools built for&#xA;the job. Notion, Asana, Trello, Jira, ..all powerful, but also bloated,&#xA;complicated, and designed around the mouse. Basecamp is a nice breath of fresh&#xA;air with it&amp;rsquo;s relative simplicity and focus on communication, but still falls&#xA;short of the fluid keyboard-driven workflow I’ve always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I kept coming back to my old favorite: Emacs org-mode. Org has&#xA;everything I love: hierarchical outlines, flexible todos, notes, deadlines, and&#xA;lightning-fast keyboard navigation. The problem is, it’s not built for teams.&#xA;Nobody else can easily see your progress. You end up either isolated in your org&#xA;files or forced back into the big, bloated tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I really want is simple: the speed and focus of org-mode combined with the&#xA;visibility and integration of a web app. None of the existing tools strike this&#xA;balance, so I’ve started building my own. The long-term vision is a complete&#xA;project management tool shaped by these principles, but the first step is&#xA;modest: an outline component for the web, inspired by org-mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Creator’s Oath</title>
      <link>https://andreasflakstad.no/posts/creatorsoath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://andreasflakstad.no/posts/creatorsoath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A manifesto for principled software builders who honor craft, integrity, and the user’s freedom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a manifesto for creators who refuse to build noise. It is an&#xA;oath to create only what is worthy. For ourselves. For those who value&#xA;their time. For a world that deserves better tools. To build software&#xA;that empower users, respect their freedom, and endures beyond fleeting&#xA;trends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
